window.MI_EXAM_QUESTIONS = [
  {
    "question": "Gina the producer caused financial harm to an insured. Which of these actions may the Commissioner take?",
    "correct": "Revoke Gina's license after a hearing concludes a violation has occurred",
    "explanation": "Correct. A Commissioner may only revoke or suspend a producer's license after a hearing that concludes a violation has occurred.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Incarcerate Gina after a hearing",
      "Revoke Gina's license immediately without a hearing",
      "Increase the bond requirement for Gina's license"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Michigan requires that a licensee complete __ hours of continuing education on the subject of ethics every reporting period.",
    "correct": "3",
    "explanation": "Correct. A licensee is required to take 24 hours of continuing education every two years. Of the 24 hours, 3 must be in ethics.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "4",
      "2",
      "1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Producer commissions may NOT be paid to",
    "correct": "licensed producers not appointed by an insurer",
    "explanation": "Correct. Producer commissions may NOT be paid to licensed producers not appointed by an insurer.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "non-resident producers",
      "licensed and appointed producers",
      "licensed and appointed producers who are sharing commissions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The act of _________ insurance does NOT require an individual to hold an insurance producer license.",
    "correct": "underwriting",
    "explanation": "Correct. Underwriting does not require an insurance license.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "negotiating",
      "selling",
      "soliciting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The act of using misrepresentation to induce an insured person to terminate an existing policy and purchase a new policy is referred to as",
    "correct": "twisting",
    "explanation": "Correct. The act of using misrepresentation to induce an insured person to terminate an existing policy and purchase a new policy is referred to as twisting.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "subrogation",
      "intimidation",
      "defamation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Under Michigan Insurance Code, Chapter 45, financial loss can be defined as",
    "correct": "loss of income",
    "explanation": "Correct. Under Michigan Insurance Code, Chapter 45, insurance fraud defines financial loss as loss of income.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "restrictive fees",
      "additional fines",
      "punitive penalties"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is considered to be an act of misrepresentation?",
    "correct": "Falsifying the terms, benefits, advantages, or conditions of an insurance policy",
    "explanation": "Correct. A licensee who informs an insured of inaccurate terms, benefits, or advantages of any policy is committing misrepresentation.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Giving back part of a producer's commission as an incentive for a sale",
      "Sharing commissions with other licensed producers",
      "Replacing an existing policy with a new one"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these actions would NOT result in a producer's license revocation?",
    "correct": "Not maintaining an adequate level of sales",
    "explanation": "Correct. All of these may result in license revocation except for \"Not maintaining an adequate level of sales\".",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Making material misrepresentations on the license application",
      "Failing to pay state income tax",
      "Felony conviction"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these BEST describes the illegal act of twisting?",
    "correct": "Replacing an insurance policy from one insurer to another based on misrepresentation",
    "explanation": "Correct. The unfair trade practice of replacing an insurance policy from one insurer to another based on misrepresentation is called twisting.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Unfairly discriminate against a person in any way on an insurance-related matter",
      "Publishing any false financial statement regarding a person or entity",
      "Using threat or force to restrict fair trade in the transaction of insurance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is the BEST example of misrepresentation?",
    "correct": "Providing incorrect, misleading, incomplete, or materially untrue information in a license application",
    "explanation": "Correct. Providing incorrect, misleading, incomplete, or materially untrue information in the license application is considered an act of misrepresentation.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Publishing a false financial statement regarding an entity",
      "Unfairly discriminating against a person in any way on an insurance-related matter",
      "Making a public advertisement that contains false or malicious information about an insurance company"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A foreign insurance company doing business in Michigan",
    "correct": "is only authorized to write business outside the United States",
    "explanation": "Correct. An insurer who is domiciled outside of Michigan, but within the United States is considered to be a foreign insurer in Michigan.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "is a company that was formed under the laws of another country",
      "is a company domiciled under the laws of another state",
      "is not subject to Michigan insurance laws"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A producer has allowed his/her license to lapse by failing to complete the required continuing education credits. The license may be reinstated by completing the requirement within ___ days of the renewal date.",
    "correct": "90",
    "explanation": "Correct. If the license has been suspended or inactive less than 90 days from the continuation education renewal date, the license will become active when the continuing education credits are reported to the DIFS. A new application is not required.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "120",
      "60",
      "45"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A producer may give an insurance applicant an article of merchandise having an invoice value of ____ or less.",
    "correct": "$50",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is \"$5\". A producer may give an insurance applicant an article of merchandise having an invoice value of $5.00 or less.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "$25",
      "$15",
      "$5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A(n) ______ company is owned exclusively by shareholders.",
    "correct": "stock",
    "explanation": "Correct. Stock companies are owned by their shareholders.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "interactive",
      "mixed",
      "mutual"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "ABC Insurance Agency is entering each applicant who purchases insurance through their agency into a drawing to win a free trip. This is an unlawful insurance practice known as",
    "correct": "illegal inducement",
    "explanation": "Correct. This is an example of the unlawful insurance practice known as illegal inducement.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "concealment",
      "false advertising",
      "fraud"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following activities require an insurance producer's license EXCEPT",
    "correct": "Underwriting",
    "explanation": "Correct. Underwriting does not require an insurance license.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Soliciting",
      "Selling",
      "Negotiating"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An example of an unfair claims settlement practice is",
    "correct": "failing to promptly provide a reasonable explanation for the denial of claims",
    "explanation": "Correct. An insurer that fails to promptly provide a reasonable explanation for the denial of a claim is committing an unfair claim settlement practice.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "requiring a time limit for submitting a claim",
      "making it mandatory that proof of loss be provided for each claim",
      "paying a claim in a timely matter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An insurer would be committing Unfair Discrimination if coverage was denied based upon",
    "correct": "marital status",
    "explanation": "Correct. An insurer would be committing Unfair Discrimination if coverage was denied based upon marital status.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "HIV positive result",
      "diabetes",
      "a mental disorder"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Andy the insured had made a deliberate lie to the insured in order to obtain a lower premium. This action is considered an act of",
    "correct": "fraud",
    "explanation": "Correct. A deliberate lie by an insured to the insurer to obtain a lower premium is an example of fraud.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "subrogation",
      "malfeasance",
      "misrepresentation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before operating under an assumed name, a producer MUST notify the",
    "correct": "Commissioner",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is \"Commissioner \". Prior to operating under an assumed name, a producer MUST notify the Commissioner.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Governor",
      "insurer",
      "NAIC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A life insurance applicant in Michigan may backdate the application for up to ___ month(s).",
    "correct": "6",
    "explanation": "Correct. In order to save on premiums, a life Insurance policy can legally be backdated up to 6 months.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "7",
      "4",
      "5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A life insurance application may be backdated to",
    "correct": "save on premiums",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is \"save on premiums\". Life insurance applications are backdated to reduce the premium.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "reduce the policy's death benefit",
      "ease the underwriting requirements",
      "increase the producer's commission"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In Michigan, legal action may be taken against an insurer for up to ___ years for failing to pay a life insurance claim after proof of loss was submitted.",
    "correct": "6",
    "explanation": "Correct. In Michigan, legal action can be taken for up to 6 years against an insurer for failure to pay life insurance claims after proof of loss was submitted.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "7",
      "4",
      "5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Under which circumstance may a minor receive proceeds from a death benefit?",
    "correct": "The minor must have an appointed guardian",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is \"The minor must have an appointed guardian\". In the interest of protecting the assets of a minor, state law requires that a guardian be appointed to administer the proceeds payable to the minor child.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "The minor must be at least 13 years old",
      "The minor must have been born in the United States",
      "The minor must not have a criminal record"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following actions is REQUIRED by a producer who is replacing an existing life insurance policy?",
    "correct": "Submit to the replacing insurer a list of the policies to be replaced",
    "explanation": "Correct. According to the Michigan Insurance Code, a producer must submit to the replacing insurer a list of all life Insurance policies or annuity contracts proposed to be replaced.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Notify the existing insurer of the proposed replacement",
      "Offer the insured a 60-day free-look period",
      "Keep replacement records on file for at least 10 years"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is NOT considered to be a purpose of an annuity?",
    "correct": "Annuities are intended to create an estate",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Annuities are intended to create an estate\". All of these are purposes of an annuity except \"Annuities are intended to create an estate\".",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Annuities are intended to distribute accumulated principal",
      "Annuities are intended to liquidate an estate",
      "Annuities are intended for the tax-free growth of principal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An annuitant dies during the distribution period. What kind of annuity will return to a beneficiary the difference between the annuity value and the income payments already made?",
    "correct": "Refund annuity",
    "explanation": "Correct. An annuity that returns the difference between the annuity value and the income payments made to a beneficiary when the annuitant dies during the distribution period is a refund annuity.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Rebate annuity",
      "Return annuity",
      "Variable annuity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How do interest earnings accumulate in a deferred annuity?",
    "correct": "On a tax-deferred basis",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"On a tax-deferred basis\". Deferred annuities accumulate interest earnings on a tax-deferred basis.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "On a taxable basis",
      "On a tax-free basis",
      "On a tax credit basis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT considered advertising?",
    "correct": "A rating from a rating service company, such as A.M. Best",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"A rating from a rating service company, such as A.M. Best\". An A.M. Best company rating is not considered advertising.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "An illustration",
      "Direct mailing from an agency",
      "A sales presentation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tim is covered under a group plan and would like to change his group coverage to an individual policy with the same insurer because of employment termination. Which of these describes the change that will take place?",
    "correct": "Conversion",
    "explanation": "Correct. Conversion is when an insured individual changes his or her group insurance to an individual policy with the same insurer at the termination of employment.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Rollover",
      "Coordination of benefits",
      "Extension of benefits"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A nonparticipating policy will",
    "correct": "not pay dividends",
    "explanation": "Correct. When an insurer offers a policy that is nonparticipating, the insurer's policy does not pay dividends.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "provide tax advantages",
      "provide a return of premium",
      "give policyowners special privileges"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How are annuities given favorable tax treatment?",
    "correct": "Gains are taxed at distribution",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Gains are taxed at distribution\". Annuity gains are typically tax deferred until distribution.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Gains are converted to tax credits",
      "Gains are tax exempt at distribution",
      "Gains are tax deductible"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Do Not Call Registry offers exemptions for calls placed from all of the following EXCEPT",
    "correct": "insurance sales calls",
    "explanation": "Correct. All of these types of calls are exempt from the Do Not Call Registry EXCEPT insurance sales calls.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "political organizations",
      "charities",
      "surveys"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the word \"level\" in Level Term describe?",
    "correct": "The face amount",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"The face amount\". The word \"level\" in Level Term refers to the face amount.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "The period of coverage",
      "The premium payments",
      "The cash value"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Converting a group plan to permanent life insurance requires",
    "correct": "the conversion being applied for within 31 days of termination",
    "explanation": "Correct. When converting from group to permanent life insurance, the conversion must be applied for within 31 days of termination.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "submitting proof of insurability",
      "converting to term life insurance",
      "paying a lower premium"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of a rating service company such as A.M Best?",
    "correct": "Determine financial strength of an insurance company",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Determine financial strength of an insurance company\". The primary purpose of a rating service company is to determine the financial strength of the company being rated.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Determine which insurer offers the best policies",
      "Determine which insurer offers the best rates",
      "Determine which agent to use locally"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where would policy proceeds be paid if both the insured and primary beneficiary were killed in the same accident?",
    "correct": "contingent beneficiary",
    "explanation": "Correct. If the insured and the primary beneficiary are killed in the same accident, the policy proceeds will be paid to the contingent beneficiary of the insured.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "children of the insured",
      "primary beneficiary's estate",
      "insured's estate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following enables a life policy to be replaced with another life policy and results in the postponement of the tax consequence?",
    "correct": "Section 1035 exchange",
    "explanation": "Correct. A Section 1035 Exchange enables a life policy to be replaced with another life policy and results in the postponement of the tax consequence.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Section 1040 exchange",
      "Spendthrift Option",
      "Nonforfeiture Option"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An interest-sensitive life insurance policyowner may be able to withdraw the policy's cash value interest free. The provision that allows this is called",
    "correct": "Partial Surrender",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Partial Surrender\". A partial surrender allows the interest-sensitive life policyholder to withdraw the policy's cash value interest-free.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Accelerated Death Benefit",
      "Subrogation",
      "Automatic Premium Loan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are an applicant's statements concerning occupation, hobbies, and personal health history regarded as?",
    "correct": "representation",
    "explanation": "Correct. Statements by an applicant concerning personal health history, family health history, occupation, and hobbies are referred to as representations.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "collateral",
      "guarantee",
      "warranty"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Donald is the primary insured of a life insurance policy and adds a children's term rider. What is the advantage of adding this rider?",
    "correct": "Can be converted to permanent coverage without evidence of insurability",
    "explanation": "Correct. An advantage of a children's term rider is the ability to convert to permanent insurance without evidence of insurability.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Increases the policy's overall cash value",
      "Coverage can be different for each child",
      "Premiums on this rider are not required until the limiting age is reached"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A tax-free Section 1035 Exchange of a life insurance policy to a different policy is permitted if it occurs",
    "correct": "from insurer to insurer and no cash is received by the policyowner",
    "explanation": "Correct. The Internal Revenue Code (IRC) enables a tax-free Section 1035 Exchange of a life insurance policy to a different policy if it occurs from insurer to insurer and the policyowner does not receive any cash.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "in the same state as the original transaction",
      "from agent to agent as long as the agents are licensed in the same line",
      "within a 12 month period"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If the annuitant dies before the annuity start date,",
    "correct": "the premiums paid plus interest earned will be given to the beneficiary",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"the premiums paid plus interest earned will be given to the beneficiary\". If the annuitant dies before the annuity start date, the beneficiary receives the premiums paid plus interest earned.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "the premiums paid will be given to the beneficiary",
      "the benefits will be given tax-free only to a stated beneficiary",
      "nothing is given to the beneficiary"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is present when an applicant stands to lose value if the insured dies?",
    "correct": "Insurable interest",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Insurable interest\". Insurable interest means that the person acquiring the contract (the applicant) must be subject to loss upon the death, illness, or disability of the person being insured.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Consideration",
      "Offer and acceptance",
      "Insurability"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following annuity payout options makes no additional payments regardless of when the annuitant dies?",
    "correct": "Life only",
    "explanation": "Correct. The life only annuity payout option has no additional payouts regardless of when the annuitant dies.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Installment refund",
      "Life with period certain",
      "Cash refund"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Shirley has a $500,000 10-year non-renewable level term life policy. If she dies 15 years after the policy's inception date, how much will her beneficiary receive?",
    "correct": "Nothing",
    "explanation": "Correct. Her beneficiary will receive nothing because the policy is valid for only 10 years.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "$250,000",
      "$100,000",
      "$500,000"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A life insurance claim which involves a per capita distribution of policy proceeds would be payable to the",
    "correct": "estate of the deceased beneficiaries only",
    "explanation": "Correct. \u201cPer capita\u201d is a method of life insurance distribution using total number of individuals. This means that all living members that are identified in the life insurance policy will receive an equal amount of the life insurance proceeds. Using per capita distribution means that if one of the beneficiaries becomes deceased before the insured, then the other beneficiaries will simply have their share increased accordingly.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "named contingent beneficiaries only",
      "estate of the insured only",
      "named living primary beneficiaries"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is considered to be the period when the accumulated value in an annuity is paid out?",
    "correct": "Annuitization phase",
    "explanation": "Correct. The period when the annuitant starts to receive payments from the annuity is the annuitization phase.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Period certain phase",
      "Principal phase",
      "Accumulation phase"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the automatic continuance of insurance coverage referred to as?",
    "correct": "renewal",
    "explanation": "Correct. The automatic continuance of insurance coverage is called renewal.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "reinstatement",
      "resumption",
      "renovation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In an insurance contract, the insurer is the only party legally obligated to perform. Because of this, an insurance contract is considered",
    "correct": "unilateral",
    "explanation": "Correct. A contract in which only the insurer would be legally obligated to perform is considered unilateral.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "aleatory",
      "voidable",
      "conditional"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ambiguities in an insurance policy are always resolved in favor of the",
    "correct": "insured",
    "explanation": "Correct. Ambiguities in an insurance policy are always resolved in favor of the insured.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "underwriter",
      "insurer",
      "producer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In order for a contract to be valid, it must",
    "correct": "contain an offer and acceptance",
    "explanation": "Correct. For a contract to be valid it MUST include an offer and an acceptance.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "be in writing",
      "be signed and witnessed by an attorney",
      "be filed with the state"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is NOT subject to income taxation under a Modified Endowment Contract (MEC)?",
    "correct": "Death benefit",
    "explanation": "Correct. The death benefit would NOT be subject to income tax under a Modified Endowment Contract (MEC).",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Policy withdrawal",
      "Policy dividend",
      "Loan against the cash value"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A policyowner can receive a percentage payment of the death benefits prior to death by using what kind of contract?",
    "correct": "Viatical settlement agreement",
    "explanation": "Correct. Viatical settlement agreements typically include a percentage payment of the death benefits to the policyowner prior to the death of the insured.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Split dollar plan",
      "Buy-sell plan",
      "Funding medium agreement"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A professional liability for which producers can be sued for mistakes of putting a policy into effect is called",
    "correct": "errors and omissions",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Errors and Omissions\". Errors and omissions is a professional liability for which producers can be sued for mistakes of putting a policy into effect.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "errors and oversights",
      "fiduciary trust",
      "fiduciary bond"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Over the course of a year, which premium payment mode is most expensive?",
    "correct": "Monthly",
    "explanation": "Correct. The monthly payment mode is the most expensive over the course of a year.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Quarterly",
      "Annually",
      "Semi-Annually"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The deeds and actions of a producer indicate what kind of authority?",
    "correct": "Apparent",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Apparent\". Apparent authority is the appearance or assumption of authority based on the actions, words, or deeds of the producer.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Express",
      "Implied",
      "Conditional"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Term insurance is appropriate for someone who",
    "correct": "seeks temporary protection and lower premiums",
    "explanation": "Correct. Term insurance is appropriate for individuals seeking temporary protection and lower premiums.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "seeks a policy that builds cash value",
      "seeks permanent protection and higher premiums",
      "seeks living benefits for themselves"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these ensures that proceeds of a life insurance policy will be free from attachment or seizure by the beneficiary's creditors?",
    "correct": "Spendthrift Clause",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Spendthrift Clause\". A Spendthrift Clause is a statement in a settlement agreement that indicates that the proceeds of the policy will be free from attachment or seizure by the beneficiary's creditors.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Protection Clause",
      "Settlement Clause",
      "Viatical Clause"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is implied authority defined as?",
    "correct": "Authority given in writing to an agent in the agency agreement",
    "explanation": "Correct. Implied authority is defined as the authority that is not specifically granted to an agent in the agency agreement, but that an agent can reasonably assume to accomplish the day-to-day activities of the job.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Authority given to an agent to act outside the scope of the agency agreement",
      "Authority given to handle claims and process payments",
      "Authority that is not specifically given to an agent in the agency contract, but that an agent can reasonably assume to carry out his/her duties"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these premium payment frequencies is not typically available to a policyowner?",
    "correct": "Bi-weekly",
    "explanation": "Correct. A bi-weekly payment mode is normally not an option to policyowners.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Quarterly",
      "Semi-annual",
      "Monthly"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the principle of Utmost Good Faith, the insured will answer questions on the application to the best of their knowledge and pay the required premium, while the insurer will deal fairly with the insured and it's",
    "correct": "promises made",
    "explanation": "Correct. Without good faith, it would be difficult to reach agreement. Without agreement, there would be no valid contract.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "issuance of the policy",
      "underwriting",
      "legal reserve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of beneficiary should be named if the insured wants to give explicit directions on how the policy proceeds should be paid?",
    "correct": "Individual",
    "explanation": "Correct. An individual beneficiary designation would be most appropriate in this situation.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Estate",
      "Group",
      "Class"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of policy combines the flexibility of a universal life policy with investment choices?",
    "correct": "Variable universal life policy",
    "explanation": "Correct. When the structure and flexibility of a universal life policy are combined with investment choices, the result is a variable universal life policy.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Flexible universal life policy",
      "Modified universal life policy",
      "Adjustable universal life policy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In an insurance contract, the applicant's \"consideration\" is the",
    "correct": "statements made in the application and the premium",
    "explanation": "Correct. The statements made in the application and the premium constitute \"consideration\" for a life or health insurance policy.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "statements made in the application only",
      "premium only",
      "offer and acceptance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A life insurance policy normally contains a provision that restricts coverage in the event of death under all of the following situations EXCEPT",
    "correct": "fare-paying passenger",
    "explanation": "Correct. A policy may contain provisions excluding or restricting coverage as specified in the event of death under all of these situations EXCEPT a fare-paying passenger.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "suicide",
      "pilot of personal airplane",
      "war"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Pat is insured with a life insurance policy and Karen is his primary beneficiary. They are both involved in an automobile accident where Pat dies instantly and Karen dies 5 days later. Which policy provision will protect the rights of the contingent beneficiary to receive the policy benefits?",
    "correct": "Common disaster clause",
    "explanation": "Correct. With a common disaster provision, a policyowner can be sure that if both the insured and the primary beneficiary die within a short period of time, the death benefits will be paid to the contingent beneficiary.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Accident indemnity clause",
      "Spendthrift clause",
      "Nonforfeiture clause"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are considered appropriate uses of life insurance for business purposes EXCEPT",
    "correct": "Protecting the business by covering entry level employees with life insurance",
    "explanation": "Correct. Covering entry level employees with life insurance to protect the business is not an appropriate business use.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Protecting the business by covering key employees with life insurance",
      "Funding an entity buy-sell agreement",
      "Attracting quality employees by offering a group life plan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are examples of a Business Continuation Plan EXCEPT",
    "correct": "Deferred Compensation",
    "explanation": "Correct. Deferred Compensation is NOT an example of a Business Continuation Plan.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Key person insurance",
      "Stock Redemption Plan",
      "Cross-purchase agreement"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are examples of pure risk EXCEPT",
    "correct": "Losing money at a casino",
    "explanation": "Correct. Pure risk is a category of risk in which loss is the only possible outcome, which is the opposite of speculative risk. Gambling is considered a speculative risk where there is a chance of either gain or loss.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Jewelry stolen during a home robbery",
      "Injured while playing football",
      "Falling at a casino and breaking a hip"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is considered to be an event or condition that increases the probability of an insured's loss?",
    "correct": "Hazard",
    "explanation": "Correct. Hazards are events or conditions that increase the likelihood of an insured's loss.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Peril",
      "Indemnity",
      "Risk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How are contributions made to a Roth IRA handled for tax purposes?",
    "correct": "Not tax deductible",
    "explanation": "Correct. Contributions made to a Roth IRA are not tax deductible.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Conditionally tax deductible",
      "Fully tax deductible",
      "Partially tax deductible"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An example of risk sharing would be",
    "correct": "Doctors pooling their money to cover malpractice exposures",
    "explanation": "Correct. Doctors pooling their money to cover malpractice exposures is an example of risk sharing.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Adding more security to a high-risk building",
      "Buying an insurance policy to cover potential liabilities",
      "Choosing not to invest in the stock market"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "People with higher loss exposure have the tendency to purchase insurance more often than those at average risk. This is called",
    "correct": "adverse selection",
    "explanation": "Correct. Adverse selection is the tendency of persons with higher loss exposure to purchase insurance more often than those at average risk.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "law of large numbers",
      "preexisting conditions",
      "risk retention"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A rollover from a Traditional IRA to another IRA MUST be done within ___ days to avoid tax consequences.",
    "correct": "60",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"60\". A distribution received from a Traditional IRA is eligible for a tax-free rollover if it is reinvested in another IRA within 60 days following receipt of the distribution and if the plan participant does not actually take physical receipt of the distribution.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "30",
      "15",
      "90"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What guarantees that the statements supplied by an insurance applicant are true?",
    "correct": "Warranty",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Warranty\". A warranty is considered a statement of fact or something guaranteed to be true. Breach of warranties can be considered grounds for voiding the policy.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Assurance",
      "Representation",
      "Promise"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following signatures is not required on an individual insurance application?",
    "correct": "Insurer",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Insurer\". On an individual insurance application, the insurer's signature is not required.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Producer",
      "Applicant",
      "Insured"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is CORRECT regarding an individual applying for life or health insurance?",
    "correct": "The applicant's medical history may be analyzed and reported",
    "explanation": "Correct. To apply for a life or health insurance policy, an applicant's medical history may be reviewed and reported.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "The applicant's medical history is irrelevant",
      "The applicant waives all privacy rights",
      "The applicant's family medical history is always required"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of rider will waive the premium on a child's life insurance policy if the parent paying the premium dies?",
    "correct": "Payor benefit",
    "explanation": "Correct. A payor benefit will waive the premium on a juvenile life insurance policy if the parent paying the premium dies.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Guaranteed insurability",
      "Juvenile waiver",
      "Waiver of premium"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An applicant's character and personal habits can be obtained for underwriting purposes from which source?",
    "correct": "Investigative consumer report",
    "explanation": "Correct. An investigative consumer report is a detailed report that contains information on a consumer's character, general reputation, personal characteristics, or mode of living and is obtained through personal interviews with neighbors, friends, or associates of the consumer.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Medical Information Bureau (MIB)",
      "Attending physician's statement",
      "Credit report"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A waiver of premium rider allows an insured to waive premium payments if the insured is",
    "correct": "completely and permanently disabled",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"completely and permanently disabled\". Under a waiver of premium rider, the company waives the right to receive a premium if the insured individual is permanently and completely disabled.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "unemployed",
      "temporarily disabled",
      "experiencing financial hardship"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An endorsement found in an insurance plan which modifies the provisions of the policy is called a(n)",
    "correct": "rider",
    "explanation": "Correct. An endorsement found in an insurance plan which modifies the provisions of the policy is called a rider.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "add-on",
      "attachment",
      "supplement"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All of these are common exclusions to a life insurance policy EXCEPT",
    "correct": "accidental death",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"accidental death\". Accidental death is not a common exclusion to a life insurance policy.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "hazardous occupations",
      "aviation",
      "military service"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An applicant intentionally lying to an insurance company on an application in order to obtain a cheaper premium is an example of",
    "correct": "fraud",
    "explanation": "Correct. A deliberate lie by an insured to the insurance company in order to obtain a lower premium is an example of fraud.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "twisting",
      "coercion",
      "rebating"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An insurance company needs to obtain personal information from a third party concerning an applicant. Which law do all insurers and their producers need to comply with?",
    "correct": "Fair Credit Reporting Act",
    "explanation": "Correct. To protect the rights of consumers for whom an inspection or credit report has been requested, Congress enacted the Fair Credit Reporting Act in 1970.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Personal Information Act",
      "McCarran-Ferguson Act",
      "USA Patriot Act"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If an insured dies during the grace period with no premiums paid",
    "correct": "the policy would be payable, minus the premium amount",
    "explanation": "Correct. If the insured dies during the grace period and premiums have NOT been paid, the policy would be payable, less the premium amount.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "the claim would be denied",
      "all past premiums will be refunded with interest",
      "the policy would be payable only after the beneficiary makes past due premium payment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Matt is applying for life insurance and requests a double indemnity rider. A double indemnity benefit will be payable to Matt's beneficiary if Matt",
    "correct": "dies instantly from a car accident",
    "explanation": "Correct. Matt's beneficiary will be provided with the double indemnity rider if Matt dies instantly from a car accident.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "dies of a stroke",
      "is injured in a skiing accident and dies 18 months later",
      "is killed while committing a felony"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In regards to a life insurance contract, which of the following statements is NOT true regarding the concept of insurable interest?",
    "correct": "Insurable interest can be established sufficiently by sentimental attachment alone",
    "explanation": "Correct. All of these statements on insurable interest in a life insurance contract are true EXCEPT \"Insurable interest can be established sufficiently by sentimental attachment alone\".",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Insurable interest is established by a court of law",
      "Insurable interest must exist at the time of the application",
      "Individuals are assumed to have insurable interest in themselves"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The suicide clause of a life insurance policy states that if an insured commits suicide within a stated period from the policy's inception, the insurer will only be liable for a return of premiums paid",
    "correct": "minus indebtedness and without interest",
    "explanation": "Correct. The suicide clause of a life insurance policy states that if an insured commits suicide within a stated period from the policy's inception, the insurer will only be liable for a return of premiums paid minus indebtedness and without interest.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "during the last 6 months",
      "during the last 12 months",
      "minus indebtedness and with interest"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ownership of a life insurance policy may be temporarily transferred with a(n)",
    "correct": "collateral assignment",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"collateral assignment\". An owner of a life insurance policy may transfer ownership temporarily with a collateral assignment.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "beneficiary assignment",
      "transferable assignment",
      "absolute assignment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the provision which states that a copy of the application must be attached to the policy when issued?",
    "correct": "Entire Contract",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Entire Contract\". The provision that the policy and a copy of an application is endorsed upon or attached to the policy when issued is the entire contract provision.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Buyer's Guide",
      "Entire Policy",
      "Policy Summary"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a reinstatement condition?",
    "correct": "Proof of insurability",
    "explanation": "Correct. One of the conditions required for an insurance policy reinstatement is proof of insurability.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Premium increase",
      "Premium decrease",
      "Changes in the insuring clause"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is NOT considered to be a nonforfeiture option in a whole life insurance policy?",
    "correct": "Interest only",
    "explanation": "Correct. In a whole life insurance policy, all of these are nonforfeiture options EXCEPT interest only.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Cash surrender",
      "Extended term insurance",
      "Reduced paid-up insurance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following riders can increase the death benefit amount EXCEPT",
    "correct": "Waiver of Premium",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Waiver of Premium\". All of the following riders can increase the death benefit amount EXCEPT the Waiver of Premium.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Cost of Living",
      "Guaranteed Insurability",
      "Accidental Death Rider"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All of these are valid policy dividend options for a life insurance policyowner EXCEPT",
    "correct": "accumulate without interest",
    "explanation": "Correct. Policyowner dividends normally accumulate WITH interest.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "reduction in policy premium",
      "cash outlay to the policyowner",
      "buy additional insurance coverage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An attending physician's statement would be appropriate for which life insurance purpose?",
    "correct": "At the request of the applicant to assist in the underwriting decision",
    "explanation": "Correct. An attending physician's statement is done at the request of the insurer when it could affect the underwriting decision, but with the consent of the applicant.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "At the request of the producer to assist in the underwriting decision",
      "At the request of the insurer to assist in the underwriting decision",
      "Attending physician's statements are mandatory during the application process"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An error was made on Mary's life insurance application. Which of the following areas do errors commonly occur on applications and for which the incontestable clause does NOT apply?",
    "correct": "Age",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Age\". The incontestable clause does not apply to the misstatement of age provision.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Address",
      "Marital status",
      "Income"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A life insurance policyowner does NOT have the right to",
    "correct": "revoke an absolute assignment",
    "explanation": "Correct. A policyowner may not revoke an absolute assignment.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "take out a policy loan",
      "select a beneficiary",
      "change a beneficiary"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the following dividend options, which of these is taxable?",
    "correct": "Accumulation at interest",
    "explanation": "Incorrect. The correct answer is, \"Accumulation at interest\". The accumulation at interest is a taxable dividend option.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Paid-up additions",
      "One year term",
      "Reduction of premium"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an insurer required to do when faced with an error made under the Misstatement of Age provision?",
    "correct": "Pay age-corrected benefits",
    "explanation": "Correct. Under the Misstatement of Age Provision, when done in error, an insurer must pay age-corrected benefits.",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "wrongs": [
      "Cancel the policy",
      "Pay full benefits as stated in the policy",
      "Bill the policyowner for back premiums"
    ]
  }
]
